mvff.com 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy

                                           Privacy Policy
                                 Last Updated: September 12, 2018
The California Film Institute (“CFI” or “we”, “us”, or “our”) has established this privacy policy
(“Privacy Policy”) to let you know the kinds of personal information we may gather when you
visit our Sites, why we gather your information, what we use your personal information for,
when we might disclose your personal information, and how you can manage your personal
information. This Privacy Policy is applicable to CFI’s network of websites, including cafilm.org
and affiliated websites (including any versions optimized for viewing on a wireless or tablet
device); your purchases at a CFI box office or via telephone, any information you submit to us at
a CFI event or to the CFI offices, all email newsletters published or distributed by the CFI; all
apps published on any platform by CFI; information collected through your use of a CFI ticket,
pass, or other CFI issued identification or RSVPs, and all other interactive features, services, and
communications provided by CFI (“Sites”), however accessed and/or used, that are operated by
us, made available by us, or produced and maintained by CFI.
By visiting our Sites, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy. If you do
not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Sites. We reserve the right to
modify or amend the terms of our Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. Your
continued use of our Sites following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept
those changes. If we intend to apply the modifications or amendments to this Privacy Policy
retroactively or to personal information already in our possession, we will provide you with
notice of the modifications or amendments.
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or don’t see your concerns addressed here,
you should contact us by email at privacy@cafilm.org.
What Information About Me Is Collected and Stored?
We collect two basic types of information from you in conjunction with your use of the Sites,
personal information and non-personal information. Personal information is any information that
can individually identify you and includes, among other things, your name, e-mail address,
telephone number, postal address, credit card, billing and contact information.
Non-personal information includes information that does not personally identify you, but it may
include tracking and usage information about your location, demographics, use of the Sites and
the Internet.
Collection of Personal Information
As a general matter, you can browse the Sites without submitting your personal information to
us. However, there are a number of circumstances in which you may supply us with your
personal information. The following lists the most common ways in which we may collect your
personal information.

    •   Registration for an account on or at the Sites
    •   Sign up to receive e-mail newsletters or e-mail alerts from us
    •   Sign up to receive e-mail offers from CFI or CFI partners
    •   Request for customer service or other assistance
    •   Participation in surveys, panels, or market research
    •   Participation in special events, promotions and programs
    •   Purchases on or at the Sites, including tickets or merchandise
    •   Entry in contests or sweepstakes
    •   Participation on social media accounts involving CFI, our Sites, programs and our brands
    •   Participation in communities, comment threads, other forums, and other interactive
        services
    •   Submission of user generated content on any part of the Sites that permit it
    •   Submission of a job application or volunteer application
    •   Any other place on or at the Sites where you knowingly volunteer personal information
Tickets and Passes
We issue barcoded tickets and passes to allow us to track attendance at CFI venues. The
information that is collected through barcoded readers is the following:
    •   Barcode ID number validating the pass or ticket
    •   Screening attendance information (title, date, location, etc.)
Through Social Media Sites
When you interact with any CFI property page or account on a social media platform, such as
Facebook, Twitter, Google+, Tumblr, LinkedIn, YouTube, or Pinterest, we may collect the
personal information that you make available to us on that page or account including your
account ID or “handle.” However, we will comply with the privacy policies of the corresponding
social media platform and we will only collect and store such personal information that we are
permitted to collect by these social media platforms. If you choose to link or login to your CFI
account with or through a social networking service, CFI and that service may share certain
information about you and your activities. With your consent, we also may share information
about your activities, including what you view on the Sites, with that social network’s users.
Non-Personal Information
In addition, when you interact with the Sites, we may collect certain information that does not
identify you individually and our servers may automatically keep an activity log of your use of
our Sites (“Non-Personal Information”). Generally, we collect and store the following categories
of Non-Personal Information:
Demographic data such as age, gender, and five-digit zip code as part of collecting personal
information

    •   Device information about your computer, mobile device, or other device that you use to
        access the Sites. This information may include IP address, browser type, browser
        language, and other transactional information. It does not include device IDs or
        geolocation information.
    •   Usage information about your use of the Sites. This information includes a reading
        history of the pages you view. We use this information to provide you a more customized
        experience on the Sites.
    •   Additional “traffic data” such as time of access, date of access, software crash reports,
        session identification number, access times, and referring website addresses.
    •   Your search terms and search results.
    •   Other information regarding your use of the Sites.
Source IP Address/Location Information
We collect and store your device’s source IP address and, with your consent, your geolocation
information and device ID which may disclose the location of your device at the time you access
the Sites. In addition, in some cases the Sites can deliver content based on your current location
if you choose to enable that feature. If you enable that feature, your current location will be
stored locally on your device which will be used by the Sites to serve you certain content tied to
your location. If you elect to have your location-based searches saved to your history, we will
store such information on our servers.
Use of Cookies, Flash Cookies and Web Beacons
Like many websites, we use “cookies”, which are small text files that are stored on your
computer or equipment when you visit certain online pages that record your preferences and
actions. We use cookies to track use of our Sites and online services. We may also use cookies to
monitor traffic, improve the Sites and make it easier and/or relevant for your use. You may
occasionally get cookies from companies advertising on our behalf. We do not control these
cookies, and these cookies are not subject to this cookie policy.
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept
cookies, but, if you prefer, you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies. If
you delete your cookies or if you set your web browser to decline cookies, some features of the
Sites may not work or may not work as designed. For more information on cookies and how to
disable them, you can consult the information provided by the Interactive Advertising Bureau at
www.allaboutcookies.org.
Our Sites use Google Analytics (and in the future may use other similar sites or services), a web
analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"), to better assist CFI in understanding how
the Site is used. Google Analytics will place cookies on your computer that will generate
information that we select about your use of the Site, including your computer's IP address. That
information will be transmitted to and stored by Google. The information will be used for the
purpose of evaluating consumer use of the Site, compiling reports on Site activity for CFI's use,
and providing other services relating to Site activity and usage. Google may also transfer this

information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process
the information on Google's behalf. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the
appropriate settings on your browser. Please note that by doing so, you may not be able to use
the full functionality of the Sites. The use of cookies by Google Analytics is covered by
Google’s Privacy Policy, available at https://policies.google.com/privacy.
Collection of Personal and Non-Personal Information From Other Sources
We also may collect and store information about you that we receive from other sources
(including by us from our offline interactions with you) to, among other things, enable us to
update and correct the information contained in our database and to better customize your
experience on the Sites.
Is Personal Information Collected From Children?
Unless otherwise disclosed during collection and with parent or guardian consent (for instance,
in some of the educational areas on our Sites), CFI does not knowingly collect personal
identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. If you are under 13 years of age
you should not provide personally identifiable information to CFI without providing us with
consent from your parents.
If CFI discovers that a child under the age of 13 has provided CFI with personally identifiable
information and we do not have parental consent, CFI will immediately delete that child’s
information from the Sites. Please contact us at privacy@cafilm.org if you believe we have
collected personally identifiable information from a child.
How Do We Use Your Information?
We use the information we learn from you to help us personalize and continually improve your
experience on the Sites. We may use your Personal and Non-Personal Information in the
following ways:
General Uses
    • Provide you with the content, tickets, products, programs and services you request
    • Post your user generated content to our Sites as you request
    • Communicate with you about your account or transactions with us and send you
         information about features and enhancements on or to our Sites and programs
    • Communicate with you about changes to our policies and programs
    • Communicate with you about your comments or posts on community portions of our
         Sites
    • Personalize content and experiences at or on our Sites, including providing you
         recommendations based on your preferences
    • Send you newsletters, offers and promotions for our products and services, or special
         events by e-mail, text, or other another medium
    • Administer our loyalty programs
    • Administer contests, sweepstakes, promotions, and surveys

    •   Optimize or improve our products, services and operations, including the Sites and how
        such Sites may be rendered on your device
    •   Detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal
    •   Perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the Sites and their
        purchasing patterns
Use of Your Ticket/Pass Information
We may use your ticket or pass information to:
    •   Provide you with the content, products and services you request
    •   Track attendance
    •   Enable effective schedule changes based on the improved ability to measure demand
    •   Notify you of any schedule changes
    •   Integrate this information with information on the Sites
    •   Personalize your offers of films, events, packages, and promotions
    •   Optimize or improve our products, services and operations
    •   Detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal
    •   Perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the CFI and their
        purchasing patterns
Except in Emergency Situations (described below) information collected from your ticket/pass is
never provided to third parties, advertisers, sponsors or partners.
Use of Your Location Information
We may use your location information to:
    •   Provide you with the content, products and services you request
    •   Personalize content and experiences at or on our Sites, including providing you
        recommendations based on your preferences
    •   Personalize your newsletters, offers and promotions for our products and services, or
        special events
    •   Optimize or improve our products, services and operations, including our Sites or the
        way those Sites are rendered on your device
    •   Detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal
    •   Perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the Sites and their
        purchasing patterns
Use of Non-Personal Information
We may disclose or share any information, other than Personal Information, in any manner that
we deem appropriate or necessary. Among other things, we will disclose Non-Personal
Information to third parties to help us determine how people use parts of the Sites and who our
users are so we can improve our Sites. We will also disclose Non-Personal Information to our
partners and other third parties about how our users collectively use the Sites.

Combining of Your Personal Information
We may use the information from one Site on other Sites, all of which are owned and operated
by CFI. We may combine information gathered from multiple portions of the Sites into a single
customer record. We also use and/or combine information that we collect off-line or we collect or
receive from third party sources to enhance, expand, and check the accuracy of your customer
records.
How Do We Share Your Information?
Except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy, we do not disclose information about your Personal
Information collected online to any companies not part of the CFI. Although, as disclosed below,
we may provide your information to certain of our partners under certain circumstances, in no
event will we sell your Personal Information as part of a customer list or similar transaction.
Third-Party Agents
We have third party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates and partners that perform functions on our
behalf, such as hosting, billing, content syndication, content management tools, social media
integration, marketing, analytics, customer service, box office ticketing, fraud protection, etc.
These entities have access to the Personal Information needed to perform their functions and are
contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of that Personal Information.
They are restricted from using, selling, distributing or altering this data in any way other than to
provide the requested services to the Sites.
Member List Policy
We do not sell our membership list to other organizations. However, we periodically exchange
member names and mailing addresses with other select nonprofit arts organizations for mailing
purposes only using a confidential service that does not permit the other organization to review
or retain a copy of the membership list. Exchange of the list allows CFI to expand our
membership base. Members have the right to not have name and address information exchanged
by responding here.
Business Partners and Third Parties
We will not share your Personal Information with our business partners or sponsors without your
consent. You may withdraw your consent to our sharing of your Personal Information with
business partners or sponsors at any time by following the opt-out process described in this
Privacy Policy.
Business Transition
If CFI becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale or transfer of some or all of
its assets, your information will be transferred to the acquiring entity. In such a situation, you
will be provided with notice that a transfer of your information is imminent, and you will be
given an opportunity to opt-out of the transfer of your information.

Emergency Situations
We may also use or disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith
belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process
served on us or the Sites; (b) protect and defend our rights or property, the Sites or our users, and
(c) act under emergency circumstances to protect the personal safety of us, our affiliates, agents,
or the users of the Sites or the public.
How Do I Opt-Out or Correct Information About Me
You may always opt-out of receiving communications from CFI or ask us to delete or correct
Personal Information that CFI may have collected from you. If you’d like to opt-out of receiving
communications from us or have your Personal Information deleted or corrected, send us a
message at privacy@cafilm.org.
What Steps Are Taken To Keep Personal Information Secure?
We utilize reasonable technical, physical, and administrative safeguards to protect Personal
Information. However, please understand, however, that while we try our best to safeguard your
Personal Information once we receive it, no transmission of data over the Internet or any other
public network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.
Your California Privacy Rights
If you are a California resident, you have the right to request information from us regarding the
manner in which CFI shares certain categories of personal information with third parties for their
direct marketing purposes, in addition to the rights set forth above. Under California law, you
have the right to send us a request at the designated address listed below to receive the following
information:
    •   The categories of information we disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing
        purposes during the preceding calendar year;
    •   the names and addresses of the third parties that received the information; and
    •   if the nature of the third party's business cannot be determined from their name, examples
        of the products or services marketed.
This information may be provided in a standardized format that is not specific to you. The
designated email address for these requests is: privacy@cafilm.org.
Also, please note that we have not yet developed a response to browser “Do Not Track” signals,
and do not change any of our data collection practices when we receive such signals. We will
continue to evaluate potential responses to “Do Not Track” signals in light of industry
developments or legal changes.
Your Obligations to Keep Your Access Rights Secure
You promise to: (a) provide true, accurate, current and complete information about yourself and
your business as prompted by a Website's registration form (such information being the

"Registration Data") and (b) maintain and promptly update the Registration Data to keep it true,
accurate, current and complete. If you provide any information that is untrue, inaccurate, not
current or incomplete, or CFI has reasonable grounds to suspect that such information is untrue,
inaccurate, not current or incomplete, CFI has the right to suspend or terminate your account and
refuse any and all current or future use of the Sites (or any portion thereof). You are entirely
responsible for the security and confidentiality of your password and account. Furthermore, you
are entirely responsible for any and all activities that occur under your account.
What Happens When I Link To or From Another Website?
These Sites may contain links to other websites operated by affiliates of CFI or third parties.
Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy do not apply to information
gathered through these other websites. We are not responsible for the actions and privacy policies
of third parties and other websites.
What About Contests, Sweepstakes or Games?
When we run a contest or sweepstakes or game relating to our Sites, it will be accompanied by a
set of rules. The rules for each contest, sweepstakes or game will specify how the information
gathered from you for entry will be used and disclosed if it is different than as described in this
Privacy Policy. In conjunction with your entry in such contest or sweepstakes, Personal
Information will be collected only if you voluntarily submit to it.
Public Areas, Chat Rooms, Reviews, and Community Areas
Please remember that any information you share in public areas, such as message boards or
feedback sections, becomes public and anyone may take and use that information. Please be
careful about what you disclose and do not post any Personal Information that you expect to keep
private. Please consult the applicable guidelines, if any, for use of our chat rooms and other
community areas for more information.
Notice to Non-US Users
Our Sites are only intended for residents of the United States, and we do not knowingly collect
information from non-U.S. residents. If you are not a resident of the United States, please do not
access our Sites or provide us with any Personal Information.
By voluntarily submitting Personal Information to us, you thereby consent to the general use of
such information as provided in this privacy policy and to the transfer of that information to, and/
or storage of that information in the United States.
Changes to This Policy
As our Sites continue to develop, we may add new services and features to our Sites and
programs. In the event that these additions affect our Privacy Policy, this document will be
updated appropriately. We will post those changes prominently so that you will always know
what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it

to anyone. We do, however, recommend that you read this Privacy Policy each time you use our
Sites in case you missed our notice of changes to the Privacy Policy.
Contact Information
If you have any questions or concerns, please send an email to us at privacy@cafilm.org or you
may write to us at California Film Institute, 1001 Lootens Place, Suite 220, San Rafael, CA
94901.
